<?xml version="1.0"?>


<h2 align="center">Making Secret Skill Checks<br/>and Will Saves</h2>

<p id="para">
	Use <b>Turn Watcher</b> to quickly and secretly make separate die rolls
	for each character by clicking on one of the colored dice icons on the
	toolbar. The computer will automatically sort the players and monsters
	on the appropriate column.
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_dice_icons.jpg" width="289" height="60"/>
</p>

<p id="example">
	The party moves into a new chamber in the dungeon. Doug
	wants to secretly roll each players' spot check to see if anyone notices a
	hidden door in a room. He clicks the <i>Spot</i> button on the toolbar,
	then clicks the <i>Spot</i> column to sort. The characters with the
	highest <i>Spot</i> checks are listed first.
</p>

<br/>

<p id="para">
	When <span id="menu_ref">Get DC on Rolls</span> in the
	<span id="menu_ref">Roll</span> menu is turned on, each time
	you make a secret check (Spot/Listen/Will), the computer will
	prompt you for the success DC of the check. Those characters
	and monsters that succeed will be highlighted with a green
	background.
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.1)</span>
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_dc.png" width="550" height="144"/>
</p>


<p id="para">
	<b><i>Customize your secret skill and save checks!</i></b> Tired of only having
	<i>Spot/Listen/Will</i> fixed column checks? Now you can add your own checks and
	add informative columns! Access the File menu, and you will see a new menu
	entry called "Stat Editor".
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.4)</span>
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_14_file_menu.jpg" width="289" height="289"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	The <i>Stat Editor</i> window allows you to create your own secret checks
	and information columns in the main screen. <b>Turn Watcher</b> comes stock
	with predefined <i>Spot/Listen/Will</i> columns, but you can change those to
	your liking. To rename a column, merely click once on a row and then click a
	second time on the column name. You may then type the new value then press
	the <i>ENTER</i> button to accept.
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.4)</span>
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_14_statwind_new.jpg" width="839" height="436"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	For alternative gaming systems that are not d20-based, you may click the on
	the <i>Die Faces</i> column and select a new dice value to use (e.g. 2d10+6).
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_14_statwind.jpg" width="839" height="436"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	The <i>Show on Toolbar</i> checkbox creates a button on the toolbar which
	will, when clicked, make a secret roll for the GM's eyes only. For example,
	the GM wants the players to make perception checks, so clicks the perception
	button. After entering the success DC, a new column on the UI appears,
	called <i>Perception</i>, and the succeeding checks are highlighted:
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.4)</span>
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_14_percept.jpg" width="1015" height="729"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	However, if you un-check the <i>Show on Toolbar</i> checkbox, your entry will appear
	in the main screen. The difference is: the entry always appears and
	contains any text you wish to enter. For example, if you now want <b>Turn
		Watcher</b> to show combatants' Armor Class, you may create a column
	called <i>AC</i>.
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.4)</span>
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_14_editor.jpg" width="600" height="348"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	The <i>Show on Player HUD</i> allows you to insert this new field into the
	player HUD for viewing by the players. The <i>Show in Monster Stat on
		HUD</i> will cause the stat to also show for monster entries. Uncheck to
	keep the value hidden from the players.
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.4)</span>
</p>

<!--
	vim: ts=2 sw=2 tw=78
-->
