<?xml version="1.0"?>

<h2 align="center">What is Turn Watcher&#x2122;?</h2>

<p id="para">
	While running a game, you, the Game Master, are expected to run your combat
	encounters smoothly and efficiently. We know that sometimes encounters are
	straight-forward and easy to monitor, but what if they become more
	complicated?  How do you keep track of Orc number 12's hit points? How can you
	know exactly when a character will bleed out? How do you keep track of a
	character's new initiative order when they delay their action? How can you
	keep readied actions straight? Is there a way to do secret skill checks and
	saves for all your characters at once? Or an easier way to mix up the action
	by rolling initiative at the top of every round?
</p>

<p id="para">
	If you have ever wondered if there was a better way to manage your
	encounters, then <b>Turn Watcher&#x2122;</b> is the solution for you!
	<b>Turn Watcher</b> tracks any number of player characters' (PCs) and
	opponents' initiative order and hit points, freeing you to run your
	encounters smoothly and efficiently. 
</p>
 
<p id="para">
	<b>Turn Watcher</b> can:
</p>

<div id="para">
	<ul>
		<li id="steps">Roll individual initiative die rolls for every PC and opponent
				and put them into initiative order automatically &#151; all with a single click!</li>
		<li id="steps">Let you enter the initiative die rolls of your players</li>
		<li id="steps">Allow for changes in initiative, such as delayed or readied
				actions, or even extra opponents that enter into combat.</li>
		<li id="steps">Easily monitor the number of rounds in a combat.</li>
		<li id="steps">List PC and opponent current hit points.</li>
		<li id="steps">Automatically bleed out dying PCs and opponents.</li>
		<li id="steps">Mark PCs and opponents as dead at -10 hit points.</li>
		<li id="steps">Make secret skill checks and saves for all characters at once
				and show you who succeeded.</li>
		<li id="steps">Allow all actions to be undone/redone.</li>
	</ul>
</div>

<!--
	vim: ts=2 sw=2 tw=78
-->

