<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- LET'S GET STARTED -->
<h2 align="center">Let's get started</h2>

<p id="para">
	It's easy to make <b>Turn Watcher</b> a valuable tool in
	your GM arsenal. The basics are:
</p>

<div id="para">
	<ol>
		<li id="steps">Create a character list of each PC involved in combat
					(you can reuse this list over and over for each encounter)</li>
		<li id="steps">Create <i>encounter list(s)</i> of opponents</li>
		<li id="steps">Import the PC and opponent lists for your encounter</li>
		<li id="steps">Start your combat!</li>
	</ol>
</div>




<!-- ADDED PLAYER CHARACTERS -->
<h3 align="center">Adding Player Characters</h3>

<p id="para">
	The very first time you start <b>Turn Watcher</b>, you will be presented
	with a blank slate.
</p>

<p>
	<center><img src="../images/tw_main_window_blank.jpg" width="550" height="202"/></center>
</p>

<p id="para">
	The very first thing to do is to input the relevant information from each
	player character (PC) in your campaign (we recommend doing this before
	starting the game).
	You only need to enter this information once, since <b>Turn Watcher</b> will
	remember it all for you. You can also update this information as characters
	level.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<img src="../images/tw_add_toolbar.jpg" border="0" hspace="10" vspace="10" align="right" width="294" height="81"/>
	To begin your character list, click on the <i>Add</i> button on the toolbar.
	The <b>Add Character</b> dialog will appear. Enter the character name,
	initiative modifier, spot and listen modifiers, and the will save modifier.
	Then enter the character's maximum hit points. Lastly, choose
	<i>Character</i> from the pull down list and click <i>OK</i>.
</p>

<p id="para">
	Repeat these steps until you've entered all the information for all your
	characters.
</p>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> Hit the <b>TAB</b> key to advance to the next field.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<center>
		<img src="../images/tw_add_character.jpg" width="328" height="338"/>
	</center>
</p>

<p id="example">
	Doug enters the stats for Shiena, a human
	barbarian. He clicks the <i>Add</i> button and types
	<u>Shiena</u> in the <i>Character Name</i> field. He then
	advances to the next field by hitting the <b>TAB</b> key
	and enters Shiena's <i>Initiative</i> modifier, her <i>Spot</i>
	and <i>Listen</i> modifiers, her <i>Will</i> save, and finally her
	<i>Maximum Hit Points</i>. He leaves <i>Current Damage</i> at 0,
	and he makes sure the <i>Character Type</i> is set for
	<b>Character</b>. Finally, he clicks <i>OK</i>.
</p>


<!-- EXPORTING PLAYER LIST -->
<h3 align="center">Exporting a Player Character List</h3>

<p id="para">
	Once you've entered all of the PCs that will be participating in the campaign,
	you can <b>Export</b> your character list. Choose <span id="menu_ref">Export</span> in the
	<span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu. Type a filename and click the Save button.
</p>

<p id="example">
	<center>
		<img src="../images/tw_export_dialog.jpg" vspace="10" width="382" height="163"/>
	</center>
</p>

<p id="example">
	Doug is running a campaign for four players. He enters each
	PC's relevant stats and <b>Exports</b> to a file called
	<i>Dragon Campaign</i>.
</p>



<!-- CREATING ENCOUNTERS -->
<h3 align="center">Creating Encounters</h3>

<p id="para">
	Clear out any existing PCs and opponents by selecting <span id="menu_ref">Clear</span> in
	the <span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu. Make sure you exported any PCs that you added
	in the previous step.
</p>
 
<p id="para">
	<img src="../images/tw_monster_type.jpg" hspace="5" vspace="5" width="283" height="71" align="right"/>
	Adding opponents to your encounter is similar to adding PCs, but you
	choose <i>Monster</i> instead of <i>Character</i> at the bottom
	pull-down menu in the <b>Add Character</b> dialog.
</p>

<p id="para">
	For each encounter, add the opponent or opponents that will combat the PCs.
	<i>Export</i> the newly added opponents to a filename appropriate for your
	encounter.
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_duplicate.jpg" hspace="10" width="550" height="118"/>
</p>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> For quick duplication of opponents, highlight the
	opponent you wish to duplicate and select <span id="menu_ref">Duplicate</span> from
	the <span id="menu_ref">Edit</span> menu. <b>Turn Watcher</b> will ask how
	many times you want to duplicate the selected character or
	opponent. You can even do this during combat!
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_ghoul_example.jpg" width="547" height="149"/>
</p>

<div id="example">
	Doug is planning an encounter where the party will run into four
	ghouls...

	<ul style="list-style-type: circle;">
		<li>
			He clicks the <i>Add</i> button and types <b>Ghoul 1</b> in the
			<i>Character Name</i> field.
		</li>
		<li>
			Then he enters the ghoul's Initiative, Spot, Listen, and Will save
			modifiers, and its Max Hit Points. He ensures the <i>Character
			Type</i> is set for <i>Monster</i>. And finally he clicks <i>OK</i>
			to store the new opponent.
		</li>
		<li>
			Next, he highlights <b>Ghoul 1</b> in the list and selects
			<span id="menu_ref">Duplicate</span> from the <span id="menu_ref">Edit</span> menu.
		</li>
		<li>
			In the Duplicate window, he enters the number 3 and clicks
			<i>OK</i>.
		</li>
	</ul>

	He now has four ghouls to engage his players.
</div>


<!-- EXPORT OPPONENTS -->
<h3 align="center">Exporting a List of Opponents for an Encounter</h3>

<p id="para">
	Now that you have entered the opponents that you want the PC party to face
	in the encounter, <i>Export</i> your opponent list. Choose <span id="menu_ref">Export</span>
	in the <span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu and type a filename, then click the <i>Save</i>
	button.
</p>

<p id="example">
	Doug chooses <span id="menu_ref">Export</span> in the
	<span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu and he exports his
	list of 4 Ghouls as a file called <u>Ghoul Encounter</u>. He then
	selects <span id="menu_ref">Clear</span> also in the
	<span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu, and begins another
	list of opponents for the next encounter.
</p>

<p id="para">
	Repeat the above steps for each encounter you have planned for your game.
</p>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> Create a few random encounter lists that you can use in any
	game in your campaign.
</p>



<!--
	vim: ts=2 sw=2 tw=78
-->
