<?xml version="1.0"?>

<h2 align="center">Keeping Track of Hit Points</h2>

<p id="para">
	When a PC or monster takes damage in combat, highlight the
	appropriate character and click on the <i>Damage</i> button.
	Enter the amount of damage and press the <i>Add Damage</i>
	button. Note that this does not change the initiative order
	as the arrow does not change.
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_damage_dialog.jpg"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	If a character receives healing, click on the <i>Damage</i> button
	as well enter the amount of healing and press the <i>Add Health</i>
	button instead. A character can also be brought up to its full
	health automatically by clicking <i>Bring to Full</i>.
</p>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> You may also apply mass damage or healing by
	highlighting those characters you wish to effect and clicking on
	the <i>Damage</i> button.
</p>

<p id="para">
	If a character is <i>Dying</i> (i.e. the hit points have fallen
	below zero (0) but has not yet reached negative ten (-10), <b>Turn
	Watcher</b> will automatically bleed the character out one (1) hit
	point at the end of each of the creature's turns (until he is
	<i>Stabilized</i> or dead &#151; see below).
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_bleedout1.jpg" width="487" height="79"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	If a <i>Dying</i> character becomes stabilized, then select
	<span id="menu_ref">Stabilize</span> in the <span id="menu_ref">Rounds</span> menu and the status
	will change from <i>Dying</i> to <i>Stabilized</i>.
	<b>Turn Watcher</b> will no longer bleed the character out after
	his turn unless he sustains more damage.
	You can also heal the character back to zero (0) or more hit
	points to prevent the bleeding.
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_stabilize.jpg" width="547" height="46"/>
</p>

<p id="para">
	When a character reaches negative ten (-10) hit points,
	<b>Turn Watcher</b>
	automatically marks the character <i>Dead</i> and grays it out.

	Note that, by default, <b>Turn Watcher</b> doesn't give turns
	to a dead character.

	You can purge dead characters and monsters by highlighting
	them and clicking the <i>Delete</i> button on the toolbar.
</p>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b>
	You can disable the skip feature by unselecting the
	check mark <span id="menu_ref">Skip Dead Characters</span>
	in the <span id="menu_ref">Rounds</span> menu.
</p>

<p align="center">
	<img src="../images/tw_bleedout2.jpg" width="505" height="112"/>
</p>



<!--
vim: ts=2 sw=2 tw=78
-->
