<?xml version="1.0"?>

<h2 align="center">Start Your Combat!</h2>

<p id="para">
	Now you are ready to actually start using <b>Turn Watcher</b> in your game!
</p>


<div id="para">
	<ul>
	  <li id="steps">
			Start the application and clear out the list of characters if needed
			(<span id="menu_ref">Clear</span> is in the
			<span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu).
		</li>
	
		<li id="steps">
			Select <span id="menu_ref">Import</span> from the
			<span id="menu_ref">File</span> menu to load your list of
			characters for your campaign.
		</li>
	
		<li id="steps">
			Select <span id="menu_ref">Import</span> again to load your
			list of opponents for this encounter. <b>Turn Watcher</b>
			asks you if you want to merge with your existing characters.
			Click the <b>Yes</b> button.
		</li>
	
		<p align="center">
			<img src="../images/tw_merge_dialog.jpg"/>
		</p>

		<li id="steps">
			<img src="../images/tw_start_toolbar.jpg" vspace="5" hspace="5" align="right"/>

			Start your combat by clicking the <i>Start</i> button (once it has been clicked,
			the <i>Start</i> button changes to an <i>End</i> button).

			<b>Turn Watcher</b> automatically rolls separate initiative rolls for every
			PC and monster and lists them in initiative order for you! It also keeps
			track of rounds in the status bar at the bottom of the main window.
		</li>
	</ul>
</div>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> Deselect <span id="menu_ref">Roll Initiative on Start</span> in
	the <span id="menu_ref">Roll</span> menu to avoid the automatic roll of
	initiative on <i>Start</i>
	(<a class="anchor" href="reorder.html">read more</a>).
</p>

<div id="para">
	<ul>
		<li id="steps">
			If <span id="menu_ref">Manual Initiative Entry</span> is selected in
			the <span id="menu_ref">Roll</span> menu, the manual initiative
			dialog displays.

			This dialog gives you a chance to enter initiative rolls manually,
			allowing you to let your players do their own rolling. The combatants
			are sorted in alphabetical order, and there are two separate columns for
			PCs and monsters. The values you see at first are computer generated, so
			you can let <b>Turn Watcher</b> roll for your monsters/NPCs easily.
			<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.1)</span>
		</li>

		<li id="steps">
			Press the <i>Next</i> button to move from one character to the next after it
			takes its full action. The character's turn is marked with an arrow (shaped
			like a sword) to the left of the name.
		</li>
	</ul>
</div>

<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> Hit Space Bar to easily advance to the next character.
</p>

<div id="para">
	<ul>
		<li id="steps">
			To come out of rounds, click the <i>End</i> button.
		</li>
	
		<p align="center">
			<img src="../images/tw_end_toolbar.jpg"/>
		</p>
	</ul>
</div>


<br/>


<p id="para">
	Some game masters and players prefer to reduce the chances for someone
	to get a 1 or a 20 on their dice. One way to prevent this from happening
	is to change the dice being rolled from 1d20 to 2d10 or 3d8-2 or some other
	multi-dice combinaison. By default the system is setup to roll 1d20.
	To change the default, select
	<span id="menu_ref">Define Initiative Dice</span> from the
	<span id="menu_ref">Roll</span> menu. Type in the dice you want to
	use such as 2d10, 3d8-2 or 1d20+2; then click Accept. Your selection
	is automatically saved when you exit Turn Watcher so you do not have
	to set it again and again.
	<span id="version_spec">(available since version 1.1)</span>
</p>


<br/>


<p id="tip">
	<b>Tip:</b> If at any time you make a mistake and want to undo your
	action, simply select <span id="menu_ref">Undo</span> in the
	<span id="menu_ref">Edit</span> menu.
</p>


<!--
vim: ts=2 sw=2 tw=78
-->

