<?xml version="1.0"?>

<h2 align="center">What is <b>Turn Watcher&#x2122;</b>?</h2>

<p id="para">
	While running a game, you, the Game Master, are expected to run your combat
	encounters smoothly and efficiently. We know that sometimes encounters are
	straight-forward and easy to monitor, but what if they become more
	complicated?  How do you keep track of Orc number 12's hit points? How can you
	know exactly when a character will bleed out? How do you keep track of a
	character's new initiative order when they delay their action? How can you
	keep readied actions straight? Is there a way to do secret skill checks and
	saves for all your characters at once? Or an easier way to mix up the action
	by rolling initiative at the top of every round?
</p>

<p id="para">
	If you have ever wondered if there was a better way to manage your
	encounters, then <b>Turn Watcher&#x2122;</b> is the solution for you!
	<b>Turn Watcher</b> tracks any number of player characters' (PCs) and
	opponents' initiative order and hit points, freeing you to run your
	encounters smoothly and efficiently. 
</p>

<p id="para">
<b>Turn Watcher</b> can:
</p>

<ul>
	<li id="steps"> Roll individual initiative die rolls for every PC and
	opponent
		and put them into initiative order automatically--all with a single click!</li>
	<li id="steps"> Allow for changes in initiative, such as delayed or readied
	actions, or even extra opponents that enter into combat</li>
	<li id="steps"> Easily monitor the number of rounds in a combat </li>
	<li id="steps"> List PC and opponent current hit points, and automatically
		bleed out dying PCs and opponents, and marking them as dead at -10hp</li>
	<li id="steps"> Make secret skill checks and saves for all characters at once</li>
	<li id="steps"> Allow all actions to be done/redone </li>
</ul>

<a name="start"></a>
<h2 align="center">Let's get started</h2>

<p id="para">
It's easy to make <b>Turn Watcher</b> a valuable tool in your GM arsenal. The basics are:
</p>

<ol>
	<li id="steps"> Create a character list of each PC involved in combat (you can reuse this list over and over for each encounter)</li>
	<li id="steps"> Create &quot;encounter&quot; list(s) of opponents</li>
	<li id="steps"> Import the PC and opponent lists for your encounter</li>
	<li id="steps"> Start your combat!</li>
</ol>

<h3 align="center">Adding Player Characters</h3>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				The very first time you start <b>Turn Watcher</b>, you will be presented with a blank slate.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_main_window_blank.jpg" hspace="10"
				vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
		The very first thing to do is to input the relevant information from each
		player character (PC) in your campaign (we recommend doing this before game).
		You only need to enter this information once, since <b>Turn Watcher</b> will remember
		it all for you. You can also update this information as characters level.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				To begin your character list, click on the <i>Add</i> button on the toolbar.
				The <b>Add Character</b> dialog will appear. Enter the character name, initiative modifier,
				spot and listen modifiers, and the will save modifier. Then enter the
				character's maximum hit points. Lastly, choose "Character" from the pull down
				list.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_add_toolbar.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10" />
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	<i><b>Tip:</b> Hit the <b>&lt;TAB&gt;</b> key to advance to the next
		field.</i>
</p>

<p id="para">
	Continue these steps until you've entered all the information for all your characters. Then click &quot;OK&quot;.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<b>Example:</b> Doug enters the stats for Shiena, a human
				barbarian. He clicks the &quot;Add&quot; button and types
				&quot;Shiena&quot; in the <i>Character Name</i> field. He then
				advances to the next field by hitting the <b>&lt;TAB&gt;</b> key
				and enters Shiena's <i>Initiative</i> modifier, her <i>Spot</i>
				and <i>Listen</i> modifiers, her <i>Will</i> save, and finally her
				maximum hit points in the <i>Max Hit Points</i> field.  He leaves
				<i>Current Damage</i> at 0, and then makes sure the <i>Character
				Type</i> is set for &quot;Character&quot;.  He then clicks
				&quot;OK&quot;.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_add_character.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<h3 align="center">Exporting a Player Character List</h3>

<p id="para">
	Once you've entered all of the PCs that will be participating in the campaign,
	you can <b>Export</b> your character list. Choose <i>File|Export</i>. Type a
	filename and click the Save button.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<b>Example:</b> Doug is running a campaign for four players He enters each
				PC's relevant stats and <b>Exports</b> to a file called
				<i>&quot;Doug's Campaign&quot;</i>.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_export_dialog.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<h3 align="center">Creating Encounters</h3>

<p id="para">
	Clear out any existing PCs and opponents by clicking <i>File|Clear</i>. Make sure you exported
	any PCs that you added in the previous step.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Adding opponents to your encounter is similar to adding PCs, but you
				choose &quot;Monster&quot; instead of &quot;Character&quot; at the bottom
				pull-down menu in the <b>Add Character</b> dialog.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_monster_type.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	For each encounter, add the opponents or opponents that will combat the PCs. <i>Export</i> the newly
	added opponents to a filename appropriate for your encounter.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<p id="para">
				<img src="../images/tw_duplicate.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
				</p>
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<p id="para">
				<i><b>Tip:</b> For quick duplication of opponents, highlight the
				opponent you wish to duplicate and select <i>Duplicate</i> from
				the <i>Edit</i> pulldown menu.  <b>Turn Watcher</b> will ask how
				many times you want to duplicate the selected character or
				opponent. You can even do this during combat!</i>
				</p>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
					<b>Example:</b>
					Doug is planning an encounter where the party will run into four ghouls. He
					clicks the <i>Add</i> button and types in &quot;Ghoul 1&quot; in the
					<b>Character Name</b>
					field and enters the ghoul's Initiative, Spot, Listen, and Will save
					modifiers, and its Max Hit Points. He ensures the Character Type is set for
					&quot;Monster&quot;. He then clicks &quot;OK&quot; to store the
					new opponent. He then highlights
					&quot;Ghoul 1&quot; and selects &quot;Duplicate&quot; from the &quot;Edit&quot; pulldown menu. When the
					Duplicate window pops up, he enters the number 3 and clicks &quot;OK&quot;. He now has
					four ghouls to engage his players.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_ghoul_example.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<h3 align="center">Exporting a List of Opponents for an Encounter</h3>

<p id="para">
	Now that you have entered the opponents that you want the PC party to face
	in the encounter, <i>Export</i> your opponent list. Choose
	<i>File|Export</i> and type a filename , then click the <i>Save</i> button.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<b>Example:</b>
	Doug chooses <i>File|Export</i> and <i>Exports</i> his list of 4 Ghouls as a file called
	&quot;Ghoul Encounter&quot;. He then clicks <i>File|Clear</i>, then begins another list of
	opponents for the next encounter.
</p>

<p id="para">
	Repeat the above steps for each encounter you are have planned for your game.
	<b>Hint:</b> Create a few random encounter lists that you can use in any game in your campaign.
</p>

<h2 align="center">Start Your Combat!</h2>

<p id="para">
Now you are ready to actually start using <b>Turn Watcher</b> in your game!
</p>

<ul>
  <li id="steps">Start the application and clear out the list of characters if
	needed.</li>

	<li id="steps"><b>Import</b> (<i>File|Import</i>) your list of characters
	for your campaign.</li>

	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<li id="steps">Next,
						<b>Import</b> (File|Import) your list of opponents for
						this encounter.  <b>Turn Watcher</b> will ask you if you want to merge
						with your existing characters. Click the <b>Yes</b> button.
				</li>
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_merge_dialog.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>

	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<li id="steps">
					Start your combat by clicking the &quot;Start&quot; button (once it has been clicked,
					the &quot;Start&quot; button will change to an &quot;End&quot; button).
					<b>Turn Watcher</b>
					automatically rolls separate initiative rolls for every PC and monster and
					lists them in initiative order for you! It also keeps track of rounds in the
					status bar at the bottom of the main window.
				</li>
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_start_toolbar.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>

	<li id="steps">
			Press the &quot;Next&quot; button to move from one character to the next after it
			takes its full action. The character's turn is marked with an arrow (shaped like a
			sword) to the left of the name. <i><b>Tip:</b> Hit the &lt;SPACE&gt; key to easily advance to
			the next character.</i>
			</li>

	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<li id="steps">
					To come out of rounds,
					click the &quot;End&quot; button.
				</li>
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_end_toolbar.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</ul>

<p id="para">
	<b>Hint:</b> If at any time you make a mistake and want to undo your
	action, simply select <i>Edit|Undo</i>.
</p>

<h2 align="center">Keeping Track of Hit Points</h2>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				When a PC or monster takes damage in combat, highlight the
				appropriate character and click on the <b>Damage</b> button. Enter the amount
				of damage and press the <b>Add Damage</b> button. Note that this does not
				change the initiative order as the arrow does not change.
			</td>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_damage_dialog.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
				If a character receives healing, repeat the same steps but enter
				the amount of healing and press the <b>Add Health</b> button. A
				character can also be brought up to its full health automatically
				by clicking <b>Bring to Full</b>.
</p>

<p id="para">
				<i><b>Tip:</b> You may also apply mass damage or healing by
				highlighting those characters you wish to effect and clicking on
				the <b>Damage</b> button. 
				</i>
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				If a character is <i>Dying</i> (i.e. the hit points have
						fallen below zero (0) but has not yet reached negative ten (-10), <b>Turn
						Watcher</b> will automatically bleed the character out one (1) hit point
						at the end of each of the creature's turn (until he is
						<i>Stabilized</i>--see below).
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_bleedout1.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
					If a <i>Dying</i> character becomes stabilized, then click
					<i>Rounds|Stabilize</i> and the status
					will change from &quot;Dying&quot; to &quot;Stabilized&quot;.
					<b>Turn Watcher</b> will no longer bleed the character out after
					his turn unless he sustains more damage or is healed back to
					zero (0) or more hit points.
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
					<img src="../images/tw_stabilize.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
					If a character reaches negative ten (-10) hit points, then
					<b>Turn Watcher</b>
					automatically marks the character &quot;Dead&quot; and greys out the
					character, automatically skipping her in initiative. You can
					also purge dead characters and monsters by highlighting and
					clicking the <b>Delete</b> button.
			</td>
		</tr>
		<tr>
			<td>
				<img src="../images/tw_bleedout2.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>
	
<p id="para">
	<i><b>Tip:</b> You can disable the skip feature by clicking on
	<b>Rounds|Skip Dead Characters</b>.</i>
</p>


<h2 align="center">Delayed and Readied Actions</h2>

<p id="para">
	<table>
	<tr>
		<td>
				If a character chooses to delay his action, click on the
				<b>Delay</b>
				button on the toolbar; the character status changes to
				&quot;Delayed&quot;.
				Once the character is ready to jump in, click on the &quot;Jump
				In&quot; button. If more than one combat participant is delayed,
				<b>Turn Watcher</b> will ask you which one is jumping in.
		</td>
		<td>
			<img src="../images/tw_jumpin_dialog.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
		</td>
	</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	If a character chooses to ready an action, click on the
	&quot;Ready&quot; button on the toolbar; the character status
	changes to &quot;Readied&quot;.  Once the PC or monster action
	is triggered, click on the &quot;Jump In&quot; button. If more
	than one combat participant has a readied action, <b>Turn
	Watcher</b> will ask you which one is jumping in.
</p>


<p id="para">
<b>Turn Watcher</b> automatically expires readied
	actions and delays when a character or opponent's turn comes up in the
	next round.
</p>


<h2 align="center">Making Secret Skill Checks and Will Saves</h2>

<p id="para">
	<table>
		<tr>
			<td>
				Use <b>Turn Watcher</b> to quickly and secretly make separate die rolls for each
				character by clicking on one of the colored dice icons on the toolbar. You can
				even sort the players/monsters by clicking on the appropriate column. 
			</td>
			<td>
					<img src="../images/tw_dice_icons.jpg" vspace="10" hspace="10"/>
			</td>
		</tr>
	</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
<b>Example:</b> The party moves into a new chamber in the dungeon. Doug
wants to secretly roll the players' spot check to see if they notice a hidden
door in a room. He clicks the &quot;Spot&quot; button on the toolbar, then
clicks the &quot;Spot&quot; column to sort. The characters with the highest
&quot;Spot&quot; checks are listed first.
</p>


<h2 align="center">Changing One or More Characters' Initative Order</h2>

<p id="para">
With <b>Turn watcher</b> you can add or import characters during active
combat. The new characters are placed at the end of the initative order. You
may move one or more characters up or down in initiative order by first
highlighting the target characters and clicking <b>Rounds|Move Up</b> or
<b>Rounds|Move Down</b>.
</p>

<p id="para">
	<i><b>Tip:</b>
	Use the <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; Up Arrow</i> to move characters up in initiative
	order. Similarly, <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; Down Arrow</i> moves characters
	<i>down</i> in initiative order.</i>
</p>


<h2 align="center">Ultra Initiative (Optional)</h2>

<p id="para">
<table>
	<tr>
		<td>
			<img src="../images/tw_ultrainit_menu.jpg" hspace="10" vspace="10"/>
		</td>
		<td>
				If you're one of those GMs that likes to mix up the action, select
				Ultra Initiative via the &quot;Rounds&quot; menu. <b>Ultra
				Initiative</b> mode causes <b>Turn Watcher</b> to automatically
				re-roll initiative at the top of each round.
		</td>
	</tr>
</table>
</p>

<p id="para">
	<i><b>Tip:</b>
	Use Ctrl-U to turn on or off <b>Ultra Initiative</b> at any time while in
	or out of rounds!</i>
</p>


<h2 align="center">Shortcut Keys</h2>

<p id="para">
	You can use <i>shortcut keys</i> to access <b>Turn Watcher</b>'s many
	features, instead of via the menus and toolbar.
</p>


<center>

<table>
	<tr>
		<th>
			<h3 align="center">File Management</h3>
		</th>
		<th>
			<h3 align="center">Character Editing</h3>
		</th>
		<th>
			<h3 align="center">View Options</h3>
		</th>
	</tr>
	<tr>
	<td>
		<table align="center" border="1">
			<tr> <th> <b>Function</b> </th> <th> <b>Shortcut</b>            </th> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Import</b>		</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + I</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Export</b>		</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + E</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Quit</b>			</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + Q</i> </td> </tr>
		</table>
	</td>

	<td>
		<table align="center" border="1">
			<tr> <th> <b>Function</b> </th> <th> <b>Shortcut</b>            </th> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Undo</b>			</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + Z</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Redo</b>			</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + Y</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Add</b>			</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + A</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Delete</b>		</td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + J</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Duplicate</b></td> <td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + L</i> </td> </tr>
		</table>
	</td>

	<td>
		<table align="center" border="1">
			<tr> <th> <b>Function</b> </th>					<th> <b>Shortcut</b>            </th> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Show Toolbar</b></td>			<td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + T</i> </td> </tr>
			<tr> <td> <b>Toolbar on Bottom</b></td>	<td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + B</i> </td> </tr>
		</table>
	</td>
	</tr>

	<tr>
		<th>
		</th>
		<th>
			<br/> <br/>
			<h3 align="center">Rounds Management</h3>
		</th>
		<th>
		</th>
	</tr>

	<tr>
		<td>
		</td>
		<td>
			<table align="center" border="1">
				<tr> <th> <b>Function</b> </th>							<th> <b>Shortcut</b>     									</th> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Start</b></td>									<td> <i>G</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>End</b></td>										<td> <i>E</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Next</b></td>									<td> <i>Spacebar</i> 											</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Delay</b></td>									<td> <i>D</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Ready</b></td>									<td> <i>R</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Jump In</b></td>								<td> <i>J</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Damage/Healing</b></td>				<td> <i>M</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Stabilize</b></td>							<td> <i>B</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Move Up</b></td>								<td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + Up Arrow</i> 		</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Move Down</b></td>							<td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + Down Arrow</i>	</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Ultra Initiative</b></td>			<td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + U</i>						</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Skip Dead Characters</b></td>	<td> <i>&lt;CONTROL&gt; + D</i>						</td> </tr>
			</table>
		</td>
		<td>
		</td>
	</tr>

	<tr>
		<th>
		</th>
		<th>
			<br/> <br/>
			<h3 align="center">Roll Checks</h3>
		</th>
		<th>
		</th>
	</tr>

	<tr>
		<td>
		</td>
		<td>
			<table align="center" border="1">
				<tr> <th> <b>Function</b> </th>							<th> <b>Shortcut</b>     									</th> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Initiative</b></td>						<td> <i>I</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Spot</b></td>									<td> <i>S</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Listen</b></td>								<td> <i>L</i> 														</td> </tr>
				<tr> <td> <b>Will</b></td>									<td> <i>W</i> 														</td> </tr>
			</table>
		</td>
		<td>
		</td>
	</tr>
</table>
</center>

<!--
vim: ts=2 sw=2 tw=78
-->

