<?xml version="1.0"?>


<h2 align="center">The list of Characters and Monsters</h2>

<p align="center">
	<img id="menu_picture" src="../images/list.png"/>
</p>


<p id="menu_para">
	The list lets you see many if not all your characters and monsters
	ready for combat. The list is composed of different columns
	explained below.
</p>



<li id="steps">Name</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	The name of your players characters and your monsters. When you
	are in combat, a sword appears on the left showing who's turn it
	is. The system forces you to have a different name for each
	character and monster. It makes it easier for you to know who's
	who and shall do what when it is their turn.
</p>




<li id="steps">Type</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	The type shows the helmet for characters and an orc for monsters.
	You choose the type whenever you add a character or monster. You
	can later change it by editing that entry.
</p>




<li id="steps">Init</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	The initiative column shows you the last initiative roll. Note that
	several characters and monsters can have the same initiative. The
	computer automatically resolves ties and it will always put the
	characters and monsters in the proper order.
</p>




<li id="steps">Spot, Listen, Will</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	The Spot, Listen and Will columns show you the last roll of
	Spot, Listen or Will. Each time you click on a Roll, the
	computer rolls dice for all the characters and players and
	shows you the results. You are free to ignore all the rolls
	that you do not need.
</p>




<li id="steps">Hit Points</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	The Hit Points column shows you the current hit points of
	the characters and monsters. You can change the Hit Points
	with a click on the character or monster you want to edit
	and a click on Damage. When the hit points go under 1, it
	shows the character or monster in grey since it is dead.
</p>




<li id="steps">Status</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	The Status column shows you the current status of your characters
	and monsters. It usually is faster to read that column than
	trying to read other columns to know the status. It will
	show you when a character or monster is dead or delayed.
	When a character or monster is in a normal state, nothing
	is printed in that column.
</p>




<li id="steps">Colors</li>
<p id="menu_description">
	Each line will use different colors to show different status, type
	and selection.
</p>
<p id="menu_description">
	A character in the normal state shows up in black.
</p>
<p id="menu_description">
	A monster in the normal state shows up in red.
</p>
<p id="menu_description">
	A dead character or monster shows up in gray. The Type icon is also
	grayed out and the status column contains the word Dead.
</p>
<p id="menu_description">
	A delayed character or monster shows up in purple. The status column
	also contains the word Delayed.
</p>
<p id="menu_description">
	The currently selected character or monster appears in inverse
	color. The line shows up in blue and the text in white.
</p>
<p id="menu_description">
	The current column used to sort the list is colored with a light
	gray. The order in which the characters and monsters are sorted
	can be ascending (little arrow in the column going up) or
	descending (little arrow in the column going down.) You can also
	cancel the sorting still by clicking on the column name.
</p>




<!--
vim: ts=2
-->
